{
    "id": "07ca90e126264a1aa9e6df665ada5c2e",
    "title": "Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She ran with quick steps to the house when it …………………………. raining.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "start",
                "started",
                "had started"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It was so quiet you ………………………. hear a pin drop.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Susie ……………………………. with her sister.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about permanent situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "lives",
                "is living",
                "has lived"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………………… in the film industry for fifteen years by next year.",
            "description": "The future perfect continuous is used to say that something will have been completed by a certain point of time in the future. ",
            "answers": [
                "will work",
                "will be working",
                "will have been working"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The patient …………………………… before the doctor arrived.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to talk about the earlier of the two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "has died",
                "had died"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………………… this with him when he came here the other day.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to talk about the earlier of the two past actions. The simple past is also possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "discussed",
                "have discussed",
                "had discussed"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was young, I .................................... play football a lot.",
            "description": "We use used to to talk about past habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "used to",
                "use to",
                "was used to"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ...................................... next month.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about pre-planned future events. ",
            "answers": [
                "gets married",
                "will get married",
                "is getting married"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "A good citizen ……………………………. all his financial obligations.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "performs",
                "is performing",
                "has performed"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………. in this office for ten years now.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "worked",
                "has worked",
                "is working"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………………………… me you weren’t coming",
            "description": "Could have + past participle can be used to criticize people for not doing things.",
            "answers": [
                "would have told",
                "might have told",
                "could have told"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If a sinner …………………………… penitence, he can be forgiven.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "feels",
                "felt",
                "was feeling"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}